Michael Mullally

Dedicated Professional With A Mark of Distinction

Profile

A devoted hard-working professional with experience overseeing a major sports franchise e-commerce business. Managed a 500% growth in sales over a 4 year period. Knowledgeable in all forms of mass media including crowd sourced content. Accomplished professional with experience in 8 sports championship events. Launched new responsive ecommerce website with integrated Point Of Sale inventory management. Maintained annual shrink percentage less than 0.50% of yearly sales. Oversaw entire retail consignment and sales for multiple marquee events including Bruce Springsteen, Taylor Swift, Kenny Chesney, Mötley Crüe, and 5 Seconds of Summer. Outgoing individual with unique perspectives and a drive to succeed in every aspect of life.

Education

University of Mount Union, Alliance, OH Bachelor of Arts: Political Science Minor: Communication New Media Cleveland State University, Cleveland OH Post-Secondary Enrollment Options Program

University of Akron, Akron, OH - Completed 30 credits towards Master of Arts in Communications

Experiences

Cleveland Cavaliers E-Commerce Manager 2013 - 2016

Managed 4 e-commerce websites including warehouse inventory management, order fulfillment, customer service, and website optimization. Planned, researched, and completed fully responsive ecommerce website upgrade. Introduced branded shipping boxes for an enhanced customer experience. Completed two warehouse relocations including planning and organization strategies. Trained and managed more than 100 different employees in a 40 day span.

Cleveland Cavaliers Senior E-Commerce Associate 2012 - 2013

Edited and published web merchandise content for Cleveland Cavaliers, Canton Charge, Cleveland Gladiators and Lake Erie Monsters Team Shop web sites. Handled incoming retail and Web customer service calls and emails. Processed orders as well as other duties assigned. Ticketed, picked and packed merchandise for shipment to consumers and internal transfer. Maintained inventory organization to ensure ease to pick.

SportsTime Ohio Associate Producer 2010 - 2012

Produced individual packages for air including player biography of Cleveland State Guard Norris Cole. Recorded and edited highlights for in-game updates and post-game show. Educated in technologies and format for STO Update Desk productions. Experienced in gathering reliable sources for OHSAA coverage. Continued work with MAC sports coverage. Produced and wrote "Inside Ohio's Head" Pilot episode for presentation to executive producers.

University of Akron Graduate Assistant 2010 - 2012

Studied communication theories and research methods. Instructed Introduction to Public Speaking course for 3 semesters. As a video/audio equipment assistant managed the rental of equipment by Communication department undergraduates. Course work including; Quantitative and Qualitative research methodologies, Sports Planning and Promotion, Politics and the Media, and New Media Production.

Good Time Trivia Live Webmaster and Emcee 2009 - 2013

Designed and maintained all web and new media marketing for Good Time Trivia Live. Built positive brand equity through Web and new media technologies. Hosted weekly trivia shows at local restaurants.

Contact Details

6505 Brookhill Dr. Garfield Hts OH, 44125 (216) 548-3506

michael.p.mullally@gmail.com LinkedIn: michael.p.mullally Facebook: michael.p.mullally Twitter: @michaelmullally

michaelpmullally.com

Skills

- Inventory Management
- Product Optimization
- Product Photography
- Customer Service
- Graphic Design
- Web Design
- Audio Production
- Video Production
- Photoshop CS6
- Indesign CS6
- Dreamweaver CS6
- Premiere CS6
- Avid Video Editing
- HTML5
- CSS3

Organizations:

Phi Kappa Tau Fraternity Epsilon Chapter Secretary

- Presenter at 101st National Convention
- Organized charity poker tournament to support Serious Fun Children's Network

Mount Union College Interfraternity Council Secretary and Treasurer

 Constructed amendments to IFC constitution and bylaws.

WRMU 91.1FM Sports Broadcaster

- Producer of Mount Union College Football game broadcasts including D-III Championship game.
- Mens and Women's Basketball broadcaster including OAC playoff games.